ZEESHAN ZUBAIR SHAHZAD

Dubai, United Arab Emirates • +971 52 328 3831 • zeeshann.zss@gmail.com

3 zeeshanzubair.com in linkedin.com/in/zeeshan-zubair



Digital Marketer / Web Developer

Summary

Excellent interpersonal communication with team members as well as with the management. Fluent in the English language as a result of growing up, and completing my education up to high school, in the United States of America. Valid UAE Driving License holder (4 Wheeler). A seasoned digital marketer with over 7 years of experience building and implementing strategies focused on social media marketing, email marketing, SMS marketing, Google Ads, SEO and Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, .NET, PHP, WordPress). Had led small to medium sized teams to achieve sales and traffic increases. Up-to-date with the latest web technologies.

Core Competencies

SKILLS	Facebook Business Manager	Google Web Webmaster Tools	Google Analytics
	Google Ad Manager	Adobe Photoshop	Adobe Illustrator
	Adobe Premiere Pro	Adobe Animate	Canva
	WordPress	HTML5	CSS
	JavaScript	PHP	C# .NET
	SEO	JSON	Bootstrap
	Git/GitHub	Visual Studio/ Visual Studio Code	SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS)

Work experience

March 2023 - Present

Digital Marketing Specialist

Meraki Developers, Business Bay, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Develop and implement comprehensive digital marketing strategies encompassing SEM, marketing database management, CRM management, social media, email, SMS, and display advertising campaigns.
- Manage the company's **CRM system**, ensuring accurate data entry, effective customer segmentation, and targeted communication strategies to enhance customer relationship management and drive business growth.
- Produce engaging digital content, including digital flyers and videos, overseeing the entire videography process from pre-production to post-production.
- Develop compelling content for **print materials**, including brochures, corporate cards, roll-up banners, and other collateral.
- Track and analyze key performance metrics related to digital and social media presence, generating
 insightful reports.
- Utilize a blend of SEO and PPC techniques to enhance web visibility, improve search engine
 rankings, and drive targeted traffic, resulting in increased organic website traffic and improved
 conversion rates.
- Leverage analytical prowess to assess the overall customer experience across various channels and touchpoints.
- Enhance campaign effectiveness and optimize budget allocation through **data analysis** and trend identification.
- Oversee the maintenance and updates of the Meraki Developers website.
- Design compelling landing pages and optimize user experience to fuel business growth.

Digital Marketing Manager

University of Stirling, Ras Al Khaimah, United Arab Emirates

- Plan and execute digital marketing **strategies** including **SEM**, marketing database management, **CRM** management, **social**, **email**, **SMS** and **display advertising campaigns**.
- Manage marketing-related communication between the main campus in the UK and our branch campus in Ras Al Khaimah, UAE in order to ensure that we maintain **brand consistency**.
- Create **digital content** such as digital flyers and videos (involved in the whole process of videography from pre-production to post-production)
- Create content for print materials such as brochures, corporate cards, roll-up banners etc.
- Monitor and report on key performance metrics relating to digital and social presence.
- Employ a combination of SEO and PPC to increase web visibility and traffic.
- Utilize the strong **analytical ability** to evaluate the end-to-end customer experience across multiple channels and customer touchpoints.
- Planned and executed production and printing drafts of promotional materials.
- Develop original content through social listening and independent sources.
- Optimize spend and campaign effectiveness through insights gained from data and trend analyses.
- Maintain and modify the University of Stirling RAK Branch website (stir.ae).
- Assisted in modification/updation of code for the Placement and Education Wing **web application** used by the students and faculty of the university to track progress (academic and extra curricular activities) of students from their freshman year to graduation.
- Built the SQA Advanced Diploma Centre website (adip.ae) using **WordPress** and currently maintaining the website.
- Create landing pages and optimize user experience for optimal growth of the business.

June 2019 - March 2021

Digital Marketing Officer

Athena Education Investment, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Analyzed marketing leads management requirements, prepared functional and technical design documents.
- Comprehensively delivered an application to manage leads using .Net MVC, SQL Server 2017 and iQuery.
- Extensively worked on SQL query optimizations and code performance improvements.
- Using digital channels to **generate leads** and build **brand awareness**. Digital channels include: the company website and all the school websites (over 10 websites), social media, search engine rankings, online display ads, corporate blogs etc.
- Design, Develop and Maintain new websites (using WordPress or CodeIgniter PHP framework) for schools under the Athena umbrella.
- Optimise and maintain the existing company website and school websites.
- Use measurable analytics to identify weaknesses and find ways to improve performance across these channels.
- Resolving all the technical & other issues on a daily basis.
- Application of Search Engine Optimization and Social Media Optimization.
- Involved in all aspects of video and photo content creation, from pre-production to post-production
- Creating graphic designs for the head-office and all the schools

November 2016 - June 2019

Web Application Developer

AGS Logistics LLC, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Coding, primarily in C#, ASP.NET Web Forms, ASP.NET MVC and MSSQL
- Specialized in Front end development with a complete responsive design and mainly focused on UI/UX
- User Experience and User Interface for the user.
- lavaScript and client-side scripting
- Creating and implementing stored procedures.
- Creating RDLC reports.
- Documentations of Software project.
- Designing and Optimizing web applications and ensuring the use of SOLID principles and design patterns
- Unit Testing, Database Flow Testing, Performance Testing.
- Read and understand complex application code and make code fixes to resolve issues.
- Involved in all aspects of the software development life cycle from analysis, design, development, testing and Implementation.
- Resolving all the technical & other issues on a daily basis.
- Self and peer reviewing the source code, preparation of unit test cases and unit test results for correctness and completeness.

Education

B.E. (Computer Science) - Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science (2011 - 2016)

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Karnataka, India

Higher Secondary Education (2007 - 2011)

Rani Public School, Vadakara, Kerala, India

High School (2006 - 2007)

Kingsway Regional Highschool, Woolwich, New Jersey, USA

Middle School (2004 - 2006)

George Read Middle School, New Castle, Delaware, USA

Certifications

- Advanced Google Analytics
- Google Ads Search Certification
- Al-Powered Performance Ads Certification
- ASP.NET and C# Certification Course